The Princess Sapphire
Knight of the Ribbon
♪ Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano ♪
The dreams I see are my secret
♪ Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano ♪
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
♪ Akai manto hira hira ♪
A red cape fluttering
♪ Uma o tobasu oujo ♪
Galloping on a horse—the princess
♪ Sore ga atashi ♪
That’s me!
♪ Lula-dula-lula-dula ♪
-
♪ Lulu laa, lulaa ♪
♪ Lula-dula-lula-dula ♪
-
♪ Lulu laa, lulaa ♪
♪ Ribon no kishi wa ♪
The Knight of the Ribbon,
♪ Honto wa hontto wa ♪
Truly, truly,
♪ Atashi nano sa ♪
It’s really me!
First Episode
The Princess Knight
The Prince & the Angel
Um, is there a kid around here with blue eyes who looks like a boy or a girl?
Nope, no weirdos like that around.
Waa!
Help!
Pick me up!
Kanabun-chan, isn't there a girl in this town with black hair who looks like a boy?
Beats me, I've never seen one. Well, see ya!
What a letdown...
I've been searching for 12 years already...
Why are you attacking me?!
Well, they just wanted to know if you're a guy or a girl.
Who hired you?!
If this water touches you, men will turn blue and women will turn purple!
That's for sure!
They ran away!
Get 'em!
Hey!
Up we go!
Giddyup!
Come on, once we start, get off your rear!
You complete idiot!
Get up!
Ah!
Oh!
Hey, partner!
Which one should I pick... Ah, this one!
Tell your boss!
No matter how much you chase after me, it's useless!
Your Highness, wake up. It is time to awaken. Whoa!
Good morning, Garigori!
What a waste of time!
That's a waste of 30 seconds!
I woke up well before the time!
I say, please stop both of these useless antics!
Your clothes are ready.
Come, Your Highness, please change into these.
What are you holding? I'm not the one wearing it!
Your Highness—!
Hey!
Good morning, Opal!
Get my clothes out.
This is good!
This is way better than these flashy, glittery clothes!
See you later, Opal!
Strike!
Thank you!
Dedicated to the everlasting prosperity
of His Majesty,
Her Majesty the Queen, and the royal family for thousands of generations,
we sincerely pray for your ever-flourishing welcome...
It's the Prince!
It's Prince Sapphire!
Not again!
Announcing the arrival of Grand Duke Duralumin!
I am deeply honored to behold your gracious presence.
It is wonderful to see you in good health as well...
What an over-the-top greeting!
Now then, Your Majesty, regarding the usual deer hunt tournament,
this year we plan to make it even grander and more extravagant...
Do we even have the money for that?
No need to worry, we'll squeeze plenty of taxes out of the people.
Bring the seal!
Press it yourself!
I'll take the army afterwards.
Excuse me... Good morning, Father!
Sapphire!
Take off your hat indoors!
What is with that outfit?
Don't you feel any shame?
But I feel so much more comfortable in these clothes...
Sapphire, you are the prince of this country.
A prince must show more dignity!
That's hardly normal!
There's a limit to your carelessness!
Then what am I supposed to say?
Good morning, honorable Father!
What's so funny...
Grand Duke Duralumin!
Ah, Lord Nylon.
That bratty prince, what a damn nuisance he is.
He intentionally tried to get in the way of me stamping the seal...
Now, now, Duke.
Prince Sapphire won't be able to act so high and mighty for much longer.
Once it is revealed that the prince is actually a woman, the throne cannot be inherited.
After all, by the laws of this kingdom, only a man can ascend to the throne.
Once the secret is exposed, this country will belong to the Grand Duke.
That prince is quite a handful. Don't lower your guard!
Rule 1: The king must not yawn in front of the people.
Hiccups and burps are completely out of the question.
Rule: The king must rarely laugh in front of the people.
Rule: The king must not fetch things himself.
He should have his retainers fetch them.
Your Highness!
Reading mangas again, I see. That simply won't do.
When I was about Your Highness's age, I read much, much better books.
About this much?
Even more than that.
Even more... Your Highness, please help me!
Your Highness!
Please help me!
Ah, look what happened.
Sapphire, where are you going in the middle of your studies?
Now, return to your room.
I hate studying!
The castle is full of nothing but old people. I feel like I'm suffocating.
Sapphire, what on earth are you saying?
I'm heading outside.
Sapphire!
Sapphire, poor child.
The fact that she grew up like that is all because of the laws of this kingdom.
When that child was born, it was right around the time these flowers were blooming.
Hooray!
People of the kingdom, rejoice!
An heir has been born!
A prince has been born!
I am deceiving my people.
Even though a princess was born, I declared her to be a prince.
But Your Majesty, under the laws of our country, a princess cannot ascend to the throne.
Therefore, we had to present her as a prince.
I know.
You announced her as a boy even though she is a girl?
It couldn't be helped.
If it were discovered that she is a princess, it would be disastrous.
That treacherous Grand Duke Duralumin would seize the opportunity to take over the kingdom.
Your Majesty, Grand Duke Duralumin has arrived.
He is right on time.
Oh dear, oh dear, what shall we do? The preparations...
The time was set, wasn't it? Hurry, the time!
Whatever should we do?
Put out some boys' toys—that way we can deceive him.
Here comes the Prince!
May you grow up healthy and strong.
That was how they managed to fool the Grand Duke,
but ever since then, Sapphire was raised as a boy.
The only ones who knew the secret were the Doctor, the Nanny, and the Chamberlain.
Twelve years have passed since then.
The secret was strictly kept.
But in order to protect that secret,
Sapphire always had to be raised as a boy.
By now, Sapphire has become completely a boy, body and soul.
Without ever knowing the joys or happiness of being a girl,
all for the law of the land.
Poor Sapphire.
Ah, I feel like I'm going mad.
Well, well, taking a walk all by yourself, my Prince?
Lord Nylon!
I hate you!
Go away!
What a cold response.
Actually, I was hoping Your Highness might give me a lesson in swordsmanship.
All right!
I am deeply honored!
Come at me with all you've got!
How's that?!
Nylon, what's next?
If I may, excuse me, but the fruit from that tree...
Like this!
What's next?
As for embroidery practice, whoever finishes this beautiful, beautiful embroidery first wins.
How annoying!
How could a prince like me do an imitation of a girl like that?!
Lord Nylon, you were the one who sent an assassin after me the other day, weren't you!
I know nothing of such a— Speak!
Don't you ever lay a hand on me again!
Hello!
Who is that?
Who are you?
I'm Tink!
Tink?
What a strange name!
I've been searching for you for 12 years.
You are a woman!
You are a girl!
I'm not a girl!
I am NOT a girl!
Girl!
How do you know?
How do I know...
I was an angel.
An angel?
Yeah, a former angel.
I came down from heaven, looking for you.
I was sent from heaven to change you back into the gentle girl you used to be.
Make ME into a girly girl?!
Just try it!
I will never become anything like that!
I'm sure a gentle girl...
Go Away!
I'll see you again soon.
That's a promise!
You cowards!
And you still dare call yourselves top-tier hitmen employed by Lord Nylon?!
Getting thrown into the river by a little brat like that!
Didn't you get tossed in too, Lord Nylon?
IDIOTS!
After going to all the trouble of buying that potion to tell men and women apart...
from Ponk of the Potion Cave and lacing your sword with it, you didn't even use it?!
Um, I tried it, but...
It worked!
It turned blue!
Lord Nylon is a man after all!
You fool!
Lord Nylon, it's Ponko the apothecary.
Ah, apothecary, I've been waiting for you.
By the way, is that medicine ready?
Yes.
If someone drinks this, will they blab out the secrets of their heart over and over again?!
Hey!
If you fail this time, it's off with your heads!
We'll do it properly.
I'm sorry.
The three of you, lure the prince out!
Lure him out?
That's right!
To the Pathless Forest!
Entice him into the Pathless Forest!
There are man-eating wolves in there!
If we lure Sapphire over there, he certainly won't come back in one piece!
And even if he does come back, before that happens,
I'll set this potion out and make him drink it first!
Hey!
Why are you telling that idiot?!
I know that!
Um, is it that way?
Or this way?
Oh, neat!
Clumsy fool!
Where did they hide?
I've wandered into quite a dangerous place...
What happened?
It is I, Duralumin.
Oh, Grand Duke, do you need something?
Actually, I have obtained a rare foreign liquor;
it's a very sweet wine meant for highborn ladies.
Well, thank you for that.
Lord Nylon, perform the poison tasting.
Um, me?
Um, I'm the one who has to drink it?
That's right, gulp it down.
All right, I'll drink it, I'm drinking it...
My Queen here have a drink.
How do i get out of this forest?
Are you lost, young one?
Old lady, please help me.
How can I get out of here?
Watch out for the man-eating wolf.
It's a huge, magical wolf that's been alive for a hundred years.
There is only one way to protect yourself from that wolf.
There is a house up ahead.
Go there quickly.
Thank you, old lady.
Soon, the drug mixed into that sake will take effect.
Her Ladyship will start babbling away—
Prince Sapphire is a girl, she's a girl!
You'll start babbling too, you know.
Because you drank that sake as well.
It's so dusty in here.
Ah, wolf footprints!
They're huge.
It's Tink?!
Don't scare me.
I am sorry.
But you were tricked.
This is the wolf's house.
That's ridiculous.
They say that wolf lures all travelers into this house and eats them.
Look, those are all hats from the people who got eaten.
How can we possibly beat it?
Well, they say wolves have a soft spot for girls.
Are you telling me to dress like a girl?
You won't be able to win unless you do.
Who in their right mind would dress like a girl?!
All right! There, this will do.
You look super cute.
No way, take this off me!
Speak more like a girl!
No!
Unless you strip me, I don't want to!
Everyone run!
It's the wolf!
Bring the wolf close and suddenly attack him!
The medicine is taking effect.
Ah, it hurts...
My chest...
Is there something wrong, my Queen?
Grand Duke, I have something to confess to you.
It's Little Red Riding Hood...
Oh my...
Are you scared?
Well, I'm weakened over here.
There's nothing that tastes worse than eating a child who's trembling in fear.
How about some flowers?
How about some cake?
Don't worry. I'll eat you up gently.
Enough already!
Stop trembling!
Geez, what am I supposed to do?!
If you were much smaller, I wouldn't be scared.
How about this size?
Even smaller?
Guess it can't be helped.
How's this, size?
So cute!
You wolf!
Prepare yourself!
You put up a good fight, kiddo.
I'm gonna crush you!
Ouch!
Fire?!
It is! It is!
Help me!
Good, good! Good, good!
My chest hurts, it feels like something is stuck inside.
Oh, that won't do, it's bad for your health.
Please open up and confess.
Spit it all out.
Um, it's about Sapphire...
Sapphire is actually...
actually?
Oh boy! I'm gonna talk, alright alright, I'm gonna talk!
That chatter potion we got from the apothecary works really well, doesn't it?
What do you think, Grand Duke?
Drugging the Queen to make her spill the beans on Sapphire...
Only a mastermind like me could pull that off—
You idiot!
Shut up!
Get out of here!
What's wrong, Lord Nylon?
Prince, Duralumin is trying to find out from the Queen whether you're a boy or a girl!
What did you say?!
Opal, I'm counting on you!
Duralumin, what are you doing to my mother?
Nothing in particular.
Leave!
Sorry to have intruded, Your Majesty.
Sapphire, you are a girl. I know that.
But there are too many evil schemes and customs in this kingdom.
Until that is gone, I am a boy, Mother.
Sapphire...
♪ Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa ♪
-
♪ Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo! ♪
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
♪ Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa ♪
-
♪ Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo! ♪
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
♪ Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen ♪
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
♪ Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen ♪
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
♪ Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo ♪
Even if devils come, even if storms arrive,
♪ tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai ♪
Our bonded hearts will never part.
♪ Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa ♪
-
♪ Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo! ♪
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
♪ Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa ♪
-
♪ Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo! ♪
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Subtitled by
SilverlandSubs
tinyurl.com/SilverlandSubs
Opening & Ending Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/
translator/natalia-arlovskaya
EAN-13 : 8-031179-423880
ASIN : ‎ B0DQ54LVY1
EAN-13 : 8-031179-426225
ASIN : ‎ B0F1V5YTQP